# Antonius Torode

2768 NW 152<sup>nd</sup> Street, Clive, Iowa 50325

Phone: 517-512-3580 • Email: AWtorode@gmail.com

Homepage: <a href="https://torodean.github.io">https://torodean.github.io</a>

Exceptionally well organized and resourceful professional with more than 5 year's experience, with a solid academic background and excellent analytical and problem-solving skills, able to handle multiple projects while producing high quality work. Experienced in software development and a strong working knowledge of algorithms and data structures.

## **Skills Summary**

■ Software Development

■ Debugging

■ Technical Documentation

■ Software Deployment

■ Web Development

■ End User Documentation

■ Coding & Scripting

■ Encryption Algorithms

■ Software Testing

■ GUI Design

■ Mathematics

■ Server Management

## **Technology Summary**

Programming: C++, C#, PYTHON, PHP, ROOT, GEANT4, JAVA, GIT, BASH, HTML, CSS, Cygwin,

LabVIEW, CAD, Qt, Makefiles, Mathematica

Systems: Microsoft Windows (all), Linux, Macintosh OS, UNIX

Software: DS9, Stellarium, OpenOffice products, Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe (Premiere Pro, Illustrator,

Photoshop, After Effects), Sony Vegas, Final Cut Studio

# Experience

# **Physics and Astronomy Computing Assistant**

Michigan State University, East Lansing MI.

Managed and maintained computers and networks for multiple departments at MSU. My responsibilities included fixing any computer related problems that may arise while maintaining or improving efficiency within the department. These included problems such as setting up new experimental camera systems, restoring corrupted operating system files, recovering lost data, replacing damaged hardware, troubleshooting malfunctioning software and more.

## **LabVIEW Programmer**

2018

2016-2018

Michigan State University, East Lansing MI.

Programming of experimental data acquisition systems for an advanced lab class at MSU for quantum physics (optical pumping) and superfluidity experiments by integrating National Instruments I/O devices to a computer system. Created accurate documentation for future developers and users of the LabVIEW programs.

#### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

2017-2018

National Superconducting Cyclotron Laboratory, East Lansing MI.

I worked in experimental nuclear astrophysics. My primary focus was with scintillator detectors and experimental setups to better understand nucleosynthesis. This involved designing, building, and testing detector systems and collecting data using photomultiplier tubes and the NSCL DAQ system. I also performed calculations and simulations written in python and C++ for determining existing detector properties and new detector properties.

#### **Physics Teaching Assistant**

2016

Michigan State University, East Lansing MI.

A tutor and exam proctor for PHY 232C, an online course taught at MSU. Assisting students in the understanding of concepts and problems via online and in person.

## **CRLA Certified Math, Physics and Chemistry Tutor**

Oakland Community College, Auburn Hills MI.

Tutor for fundamental concepts and ideas of mathematics, physics and chemistry.

#### **Condensed Matter Physics Research**

2013

Oakland University, Auburn Hills MI.

Extensively studied Raman spectroscopy and graphite/graphene under high pressures. Performed a Raman spectroscopy experiment on graphene using a diamond anvil cell. Personally designed and set up resistivity experiments to confirm findings. Presented research in a professional and comprehensive manner in front of an audience.

**Data Research Analyst** 2011-2013

CLRS, Inc., Southfield MI.

Performed Data analysis of different financial markets including the General Motors commercial car market. Learned and filled in for other positions when needed, including management duties. Performed analysis of economic markets and businesses. In depth research of Las Vegas casino populations. Analyzed business functionality and efficiency and improved upon them by shortening data verification process.

d0sag3-Films 2010-Present

Home Business

d0sag3-Films is a video editing and graphic design title I created. Paid projects for Detroit In Focus but also many personal projects. Many of my projects can be viewed at https://torodean.github.io/D3F

#### Peer Reviewed Publications

- Jan 2018 "Software Development to Determine the Optimal Parameters of a Tape Transport System." Student Journal of Physics - International Version - Vol. 7. No. 1.
- Jan-March 2018 Indian Association of Physics Teachers. Jun 2017 "Exploration of the Quantum Casimir Effect." Student Journal of Physics - Inter- national Version - Vol. 6. No. 2. April-June 2017 - Indian Association of Physics Teachers.

# Other Publications and Projects

- 2018 "Multiple Integrated Applications (MIA)." Program created for further development of application design. Contains mathematical functions, encryption algorithms, windows key code simulations, a comprehensive workout generation system, and more.
- Oct 2017 "Characterizing a Tape Station and Beta Detector For Radioactive Isotope Beam Experiments." Conference Poster presented at the Fall Meeting of the Division of Nuclear Physics of the American Physical Society
- 2017 "Generations of Nuclear Activity (GINA)." Program created for performing nuclear decay calculations for a new radioactive transport system at the NSCL.
- 2017 "Local Operations Listing Agent (LOLA)." Program created for improved efficiency and computer database management at MSU.
- 2016 "Antonius' Handbook." Comprehensive reference of useful formulas, constants, units and definitions. Self-Published: Free book download for current version. https://torodean.github.io/AHandbook.html

#### Education

**Degree in Biblical Studies,** *Ambassador Bible College*, Milford OH.

2018-2019

Religious studies pertaining to the history and contents of the Bible and other religions.

B.S., Physics, Mathematics (Dual Majors), Michigan State University, East Lansing MI.

2015—2018

Graduated with an undergraduate physics degree and mathematics degree.

**Undergraduate Studies**, *Oakland Community College*, Auburn Hills MI.

2013—2015

General studies as well as math/sciences up to and including Calculus III, Differential Equations, Engineering Physics II and General Chemistry II (4.0 in all).

2013-2015